(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-17T05:51:21.987572",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
防腐レス 羞部の古傷
Antiseptic-free, old scars of shameful parts
えぐる セレブ 騎乗位
Gouging out, celebrity cowgirl position
サディスティック・ウーマン
Sadistic woman
馬並みのアレに歯立てて乾杯
Biting into that horse-like thing, a toast!
間髪入れずに合体
Coupling without a moment's pause
100発喋らっして安泰
Speaking 100 rounds for peace of mind
未発達の体 見渡せば
Looking over undeveloped bodies,
ミミズ腫れオンパレード
it's a parade of welts.
ねっちりナポリタン むさぼりニタニタ
Greedy Neapolitan, devouring with a greasy grin
マニアがパスしてマニア
Passes made by maniacs for maniacs
笑ったマリア 「ガバス」がマネーや！
Maria laughed, "Gabas" is money!
おあずけ カードキー 「ひざまづき お泣き」
Withheld key card, "Kneel and weep"
くるぶし キメて マスバスター あざむく
Fixating on ankles, mass-busting and deceiving
踏んづけて まぶす 手付かずの卵巣
Trampling and dusting untouched ovaries
生垣に化んで 乾麺乾麺に若返り 引いて優越感 粕かすに明かす
Disguising as hedges, reverting to dry noodles, drawing out superiority, revealing to the dregs
即装備 酸素 湧き めぐらす ソング
Immediate equipment, oxygen welling up, circulating song
聖地 なびかす 天狗 謳う だす
Making sacred grounds flutter, tengu singing out
おべおべにグラビアじゃ変貌 愛人 追われ 俊敏 jumping!
Transformed into a cowering gravure model, chased lover, nimble jumping!
おべおべにグラビアじゃ変貌 マスゴミさん 恰好の餌食さ
Transformed into a cowering gravure model, the media's prime prey
食らう 罵声 病んだ 性
Devouring abuse, diseased sexuality
s と s の 痛み 合戦
A battle of pain between s and s
あんた 奴隷 おまえ 奴隷
You're a slave, you're a slave
放送禁止 モード 発生！！
Broadcast-prohibited mode activated!!
合法 デート 肛門 dead
Legal date, anal dead
首 すじ 伝う ロープ 踊れ 自ら hey! fuxx man
Rope tracing down the neck, dance yourself, hey! fuxx man
青 アザ ！！ 爪 爪 to many 女 傷
Blue bruise!! Tsumu tsumu to many female scars
法律 狂わ して 濡らす が いい ． ． ．
It's fine to drive laws crazy and get soaked...
爪爪爪 腕 に 女 kiss
Tsumu tsumu tsumu, woman kiss on the arm
汚物 転がし て 野垂る が いい ． ． ．
It's fine to roll filth and drop dead in the street...
法律 狂わ して 濡らす が いい ． ． ．
It's fine to drive laws crazy and get soaked...
なんなんだろ 気になる夜
I wonder what it is, on this worrying night...
キミへの この思い 便せんにね 書いてみるよ
writing these feelings for you on stationery...
なんなんだろ 気になる夜
I wonder what it is, on this worrying night
キミへの この思い
writing these feelings for you
便せんにね 書いてみるよ
on stationery...
もしもして 気まぐれかもしれない
This might just be on a whim
それなのに枚数だけ 増えていくよ
yet the number of pages keeps increasing
好きの確率 わりだす計算式
An equation to calculate the odds of love
あればいいのに
I wish there was one
キラキラひかる 願い事も
My shining wishes, all the messy troubles
グチャグチャへたる 悩み事も ソーダホッチキスにとじちゃおー
I'll just staple everything together!
はじまりだけは 軽いノリで
It started out with a light mood
しらないうちに あつくなって
before I knew it, it got heated up
もう針なんだか 通らない
and now staples won't even go through
ララ☆また明日
Lala☆ See you tomorrow
どうしようかな 読み返すのはずかしい
What should I do? It's embarrassing to read it back
あれこれと 便せんにね 書きたいくせに
even though I want to write all sorts of things on stationery
気持ちごと ごみ箱行きじゃないんだ
It's not like these feelings are going in the trash
この胸がせつないから 持ってようかな
because my heart aches so much, maybe I should keep them
今の気持ちをあらわす 辞書にもない言葉さがすよ
searching for words not even in the dictionary to express how I feel right now
ワクワクしちゃう 計画とか グダグダすぎる 展開とか
Plans that get me excited, overly messy developments...
ぜんぶホッチキスにとじちゃおー
I'll just staple everything together!
今日の出来事 思い出して
Remembering what happened today
いつも心がつーんとなって
always makes my heart tighten
もう針がないから買わなくちゃ
so I need to buy more staples
ララ☆また明日
Lala☆ See you tomorrow
キラキラひかる 願い事も
My shining wishes, all the messy troubles
グチャグチャへたる 悩み事も
I'll just staple everything together!
そーだホッチキスにとじちゃおー
(Music continues)
はじまりだけは 軽いノリで
It started out with a light mood
しらないうちに あつくなって もう針なんだか 通らない
before I knew it, it got heated up and staples won't even go through
どうしようかな 読み返すのはずかしい あれこれと 便せんにね 書きたいくせに
What should I do? It's embarrassing to read it back even though I want to write all sorts of things...
気持ちごと ごみ箱行きじゃないんだ この胸がせつないから
It's not like these feelings are going in the trash because my heart aches so much...
ガス感情の塊
A lump of pressurized emotions
一人占めほどほどぐらい
keeping it all to myself is enough
すべて比較そのクセ
comparing everything, that habit
誰の愛で抑制
suppressed by whose love?
必死！ 本音じゃあ明けない
Desperate! I can't reveal my true feelings
愚痴愚痴になり下がる
reduced to just grumbling
六感でろくでもなし
good for nothing with six senses
やるため息増し増し
sighs increasing more and more
ウィンダフル フリージング フリージング
Wonderful freezing, freezing...
まぜるなきけん
Do not mix!
おどれおのえらへファックマン
Dance and gloat, you fuckman
おあざとねずみ
Calculating rat
トゥーメニーおなきず
Too many emotional scratches
ほりくるわしてぬらすが言い
Digging around and getting wet is fine
つめつめつめんでいおなきず
Packed, packed, packed and teary emotional scratches
おぶすころがしてのざるが言い
Knocking over the ugly and...
はぁ…はぁ…はぁ…
Haah... haah... haah...
あーこんなにがんばってるのに誰も聞いてくれないね
Ah, even though we're trying so hard, nobody's listening to us.
悲しいよ…
It's so sad...
私たち才能ないのかな？ 一生懸命なのに…
Do we have no talent? Even though we're giving it our all...
え？ うそ、上手だったよ！
Eh? No way, you were good!
よかったぺこだよ！感動した！
It was great peko! I was moved!
あなたは学年一歌がうまい知らんぬいフレアさん
And you are Flare-san, who's supposedly the best singer in our year.
どうも。
Hello.
そしてあなたはうさ耳が生えていることでかなりの集客効果があるうさだよぺこらさん どうも
And you, Pekora-san, who has a huge drawing power just from having rabbit ears. Hello.
ねぇねぇ、よかったら一緒にバンド？
Hey hey, if you want, want to form a band together?
そして月日は流れ、過酷な練習を乗り越えた4人は文化祭のステージに立つのであった
And time passed, and the four of them, having overcome harsh practice, stood on the cultural festival stage.
キミを見ていると いつもハートドキドキ
Whenever I look at you, my heart throbs
揺れる思いは マシュマロみたいにふわふわ
and my swaying feelings are fluffy like marshmallows
いつもがんばる キミの横顔 ずっと見ていても
You're always working hard, even when I gaze at your profile
気づかないよね
you never notice, do you?
夢の中なら 二人の距離縮められるのにね
In my dreams, we could close the distance between us...
おあー カミサマおねがい
Ah, dear God, please
二人だけの ドリームタイムください
give us a dream time just for the two of us!
お気に入りのうさぎちゃん抱いて 今夜も おやすみ
Cuddling my favorite bunny plushie, good night tonight too!
ふわふわタイム ふわふわタイム
Fluffy time, fluffy time...
ふわふわタイム
Fluffy time...
キミをみると いつもハートDOKI☆DOKI
When I look at you, my heart always goes thump-thump!
揺れる想いはマシュマロみたいにふわふわ
My swaying feelings are fluffy like marshmallows.
いつもがんばるキミの横顔
Your profile when you're always working hard
ずーっと見ても気づかないだね
You don't notice even if I keep looking.
夢の中なら
If it's in a dream,
ふたりの距離縮められるのにね
we could close the distance between us.
ああ カミサマお願い
Ah, O God, please,
ふたりだけのDream Timeください
give me Dream Time just for the two of us.
お気に入りのうさちゃん抱いて
Hugging my favorite bunny,
今夜もオヤスミ
I'll go to sleep again tonight.
ふわふわ時間
Fluffy Time,
Fluffy Time.
ああ カミサマお願い
Ah, O God, please,
一度だけのMIRACLE TIMEください
give me just one Miracle Time.
もしすんなり話せば
If we talk smoothly,
そのあとは…どうにかなるよね
after that... things will work out somehow, right?
とっておきのくまちゃん出したし今夜は大丈夫かな
I brought out my special teddy bear, will I be okay tonight?
もう少し勇気ふるって
Gathering a little more courage,
自然に話せば
if I talk naturally,
何か変わるのかな?
I wonder if anything will change?
そんな気がするけど
I feel like that, but
だけどそれが一番難しいのよ
that's the hardest part of all.
話のきっかけとかどうしようって
Wondering how to start a conversation,
てんやわんや考えてる時点で
at the point when I'm panicking and thinking it over,
全然自然じゃないよね
it's totally unnatural, right?
あぁ もういいや寝ちゃお寝ちゃお寝ちゃおねっ!
Ah, screw it, time to sleep, sleep, sleep!
ああ カミサマお願い
Ah, O God, please,
一度だけのMIRACLE TIMEください
give me just one Miracle Time.
もしすんなり話せば
If we talk smoothly,
そのあとは…どうにかなるよね
after that... things will work out somehow, right?
ふわふわ時間
Fluffy Time,
Fluffy Time.
God knows...
渇いた心で駆け抜ける
Running through with a parched heart,
ごめんね 何もできなくて
I'm sorry I couldn't do anything.
痛みを分かち合うことさえ
Even sharing our pain
あなたは許してくれない
you wouldn't let me do.
無垢に生きるため振り返らず
Living innocently without looking back,
背中向けて行ってしまう
you turn your back and leave.
on the lonely rail
私ついていくよ
I will follow you.
どんな辛い世界の闇の中でさえ
No matter how harsh the darkness of this world may be,
あなたは輝いて超える未来の果て
you shine beyond the end of the future.
弱さ故に魂こわされないように
So my soul won't be broken by weakness,
my way 重なるよ いまふたりに God bless...
My way, converging now upon us both, God bless...
届けて熱い想いは
Convey these burning feelings,
現実溶かしてさめよう
melting reality and fading away.
会いたい気持ちに理由はない
There's no reason for wanting to see you,
あふれだす Lovin' you
overflowing with Lovin' you.
せめて美しい夢だけを
At least while dreaming only of beauty,
描きながら追いかけよう
let's chase after it.
渇いた心で駆け抜ける
With a thirsting heart, I run through...
ごめんね 何もできなくて
I'm sorry I couldn't do anything for you.
痛みを分かち合うことさえ
Even sharing our pain,
あなたは許してくれない
you wouldn't forgive me.
無垢に生きるため振り返らず
To live innocently without looking back,
背中向けて行ってしまう
turning your back and walking away
on the lonely rail
私はついていくよ どんな辛い
I will follow you, through whatever painful
世界の闇の中でも
darkness of the world there may be.
きっとあなたは輝いて
Surely you will shine on,
超える未来の果て
beyond the limits of the future.
弱さ故に魂犯されないように my way
So my soul won't be tainted by weakness, my way—
重なるよ いまふたりに
overlapping now, for the two of us,
God bless...
届けて熱くなる想いは
Reach out, feelings growing hot,
現実溶かしてさめよう
melting reality away.
会いたい気持ちに理由はない
There's no reason for wanting to see you,
あなたへあふれだす Lovin' you
overflowing toward you, Lovin' you.
せめて美しい夢だけを
At least while sketching only beautiful dreams,
描きながら追いかけよう
let's chase after them
for your lonely heart
やめて嘘はあなたらしくないよ
Stop it, lies aren't like you at all.
目を見てこれからのことを話そう
Look me in the eye and let's talk about the future.
私覚悟してる 暗い未来だって
I am prepared, even if our future is dark;
強くなって運命変えられるかもね
maybe I can become strong enough to change fate,
my wish
叶えたいのに すべては
Though I want to make it happen, everything is...
God knows...
あなたがいて 私がいて
You were there, I was there,
ほかの人は消えてしまった
and everyone else had vanished.
淡い夢の美しさを描きながら
While tracing the beauty of a fleeting dream,
傷跡をなぞる
tracing the scars.
だから私ついていくよ
That's why I will follow you,
どんな辛い世界の闇の中でも
through whatever painful darkness of the world,
きっとあなたは輝いて
surely you will shine on,
超える未来の果て
beyond the limits of the future.
弱さ故に魂冒されないように
So my soul won't be tainted by weakness,
my way
my way—
重なるよ いまふたりに
overlapping now, for the two of us,
God bless...
いや、文化祭も終わったね！
Man, the school festival is finally over!
お疲れ様でした！お疲れ様でしたー！
Good job everyone! Great job!
いやみんな、あのさ、今度はさ、もう学校なんて狭い箱は飛び出さない？
Hey everyone, you know what? Next time, why don't we break out of a cramped box like a school?
え、どうしたの？どこ行きたいの？
Eh, what's wrong? Where do you want to go?
路上に行こう、路上に行こう！路上行こう！
Let's go to the street! Let's play on the street!
じゃあみんな、次は私服で集合ね！
Alright everyone, next time let's meet in our regular clothes!
私服だ！やったー！やったー！私服！またね！
Casual clothes! Yay! Yay! Casual clothes! See ya!
え、そこまで？行くぞぺこら、ぱいっ！
Wait, right now? Let's go Pekora, pai!
ああ、お疲れ様です！
Ah, good work everyone!
今日も頑張ろうね！頑張ろうね！
Let's do our best today too! Let's do our best!
（こいつ、私服がこれってマジか？）
(Is she seriously wearing that as casual clothes?)
え？頑張ろうね？ってか、マリン、目大丈夫？なんか怪我してない？
Eh? Do our best? Also, Marine, is your eye okay? Are you hurt or something?
あ、これ？これ全然大丈夫なやつ！これ大丈夫なやつ！
Ah, this? This is totally fine! This is fine!
痛くない？
Doesn't it hurt?
いややるやるやる！大丈夫！
No, I'll do it, I'll do it! It's fine!
頑張ろうね！頑張ろう！
Let's do our best! Let's do our best!
君とのラブストーリー それは予想通り
Our love story, it was just as expected.
いざ始まればひとり芝居だ ずっとそばにいたって 結局ただの観客だ
Once it began, it was a one-man show. Even though I was always by your side, in the end I was just a spectator.
感情のないアイソーリー それはいつもの通り 慣れてしまえば悪くはないけど
An emotionless "I'm sorry," business as usual. Once you get used to it, it's not so bad, but
君とのロマンスは人生柄 続きはしないことを知った
I knew that our romance wouldn't last forever by nature of life.
もっと違う設定で もっと違う関係で
If only in a different setting, in a different relationship,
君とのラブストーリー
Our love story,
それは予想通り
it was as expected.
いざ始まればひとり芝居だ
Once it began, it was a one-man show.
もっと違う設定で
If only we could meet in a different setting,
もっと違う関係で
in a different relationship,
出会える世界線 選べたらよかった
in a timeline we could choose.
グッバイ
Goodbye.
君の運命のヒトは僕じゃない
I'm not the person destined for you.
つらいけど否めない
It's painful, but I can't deny it.
でも離れ難いのさ
Still, it's hard to let go.
その髪に触れただけで
Just touching your hair...
痛いや いやでも
hurts. No, but...
甘いな いやいや
It's sweet. No, no.
グッバイ
Goodbye.
それじゃ僕にとって君は何?
So what am I to you?
答えは分からない
I don't know the answer,
分かりたくもないのさ
and I don't want to know.
たったひとつ確かなことがあるとするならば
If there's one thing I'm certain of,
「君は綺麗だ」
"You're beautiful."
誰かが偉そうに語る恋愛の論理
Someone pretentiously talks about the logic of love,
何ひとつとしてピンとこなくて
but nothing resonates with me at all.
飛行機の窓から見下ろし知らない町の夜景みたいだ
Like looking down from an airplane window at an unfamiliar city's night view.
もっと違う設定で
If only we had a different setting,
もっと違う関係で
a different relationship,
出会える世界線 選べたらよかった
a different timeline where we could meet.
伊達って純な心で かなった恋を抱きしめて
With a pure heart, holding onto a love that came true,
好きだとか無責任に言えたらいいな
I wish I could irresponsibly say "I love you."
そう願っても虚しいのさ
But wishing for that is futile.
グッバイ
Goodbye.
つないだ手の向こうにエンドライン
Beyond the hands we held is an end line.
引き伸ばすたびにうずき出す未来には君はいない
You're not in the future that throbs every time I stretch it out.
その事実だけにcry
Crying over that fact alone,
そりゃ苦しいよな
of course it's painful.
グッバイ
Goodbye.
君の運命のヒトは僕じゃない
I'm not the person destined for you.
つらいけど否めない
It's painful, but I can't deny it.
でも離れ難いのさ
Still, it's hard to let go.
その髪に触れただけで
Just touching your hair...
痛いや いやでも
hurts. No, but...
甘いな いやいや
It's sweet. No, no.
グッバイ
Goodbye.
それじゃ僕にとって君は何?
So what am I to you?
答えは分からない
I don't know the answer,
分かりたくもないのさ
and I don't want to know.
たったひとつ確かなことがあるとするならば
If there's one thing I'm certain of,
「君は綺麗だ」
"You're beautiful."
舞踏会の夜が
The night of the ball...
終わるような
is ending.
苦い夜明けだ
A bitter dawn.
とても綺麗だ
It's so beautiful.
ねぇ思い出のカケラに名前をつけて保存するなら
Hey, if we name and preserve fragments of our memories,
“宝物”がぴったりだね
"Treasure" fits perfectly.
そうココロの容量がいっぱいになるくらい
Yes, we spent every heartbeat-colored day
過ごしたねトキメキ色の毎日
as if our hearts were filling to capacity.
なじんだ制服と上履き ホワイトボードの落書き
We got used to the uniforms, indoor shoes, and whiteboard scribbles.
明日の入り口に置かなくちゃいけないのかな
We wonder if we have to leave them at tomorrow's entrance.
でもね、会えたよ!すてきな天使に
But you know, we met a wonderful angel!
卒業は終わりじゃない これからも仲間だから
Graduation is not the end, because we'll be friends forever.
ねえ 思い出のカケラに 名前をつけて保存するなら “宝物”がぴったりだね
Hey, if we could put our names on a piece of our memories... treasure would be the exact word.
そう ココロの容量がいっぱいになるくらいに過ごしたね ときめき色の毎日
Right, these excitement-colored days were so full.
でもね 出会えたよ 素敵な天使に
But hey, we met a wonderful angel!
卒業は 終わりじゃない これからも 仲間だから
Graduation isn't the end, we're buddies from here on out!
一緒の写真たち おそろいのキーホルダー いつまでも 輝いてる
Together in photos, our matching keychains will shine forever.
ずっと その笑顔 ありがとう
Thank you for your smiles!
ねえ 桜の木も ちょっと 背丈が伸びたみたい
Hey, the cherry trees seem like they've grown a bit too.
見えない ゆっくりなスピードでも きっと あの空 は 見てたね
Though it's a slow speed, I'm sure the sky saw it all.
何度も つまずいたこと それでも 最後まで 歩けたこと
All the times we tripped, and yet we walked till the end.
このままで いられたら いいのに な
If we could just stay like this...
でもね ふれたよ 愛す べき 天使 に
But hey, we were touched by a lovely angel!
ただいま って言いたくなる この 場所 は 変わらないよ
This place will never change.
メールの受信箱 丸したカレンダー
Our email inboxes, circled dates on calendars,
とびきり の 夢 と 出会い てくれた 音楽 に ありがとう
we met an extraordinary dream—thank you to music.
離れて ても 同じ空 見上げて ユニゾン で 歌おう ！
Even if we're apart, looking up at the same sky, let's sing in unison!
でもね 会えたよ 素敵な 天使 に 卒業は 終わりじゃない
But hey, we met a wonderful angel! Graduation isn't the end!
これからも 仲間だから 大好きって言うなら 大大好きって返すよ
We're buddies from here on out! If you love us, we love you back!
ずっと 永遠に 一緒だよ
We'll be together forever and ever!
君たち あんまり上手くないね
You guys aren't very good at this,
でも すごく楽しそうだったよ
but it looked so fun!
何この歌？ 何？ 誰？
What, this song? Who is this?
僕の事務所に入らないかい？
Would you like to join my agency?
えっ！？ うっそ！
Huh?! No way!
これ、これって、す… す、す、す…
Wait, is this...
め、め、め、スカウト！？
No way, a scout?!
やったー！
Yaaay!
背後にわシャッターの壁 指先は鉄の匂い
There's a wall of shutters behind me, my fingertips smell like steel.
進めはじけの道コンデショウ find a way ここから
Move ahead, strum those strings, find a way from here!
found out 見つける rockをかなでろ
You'll find what you're looking for, play some rock,
遠くを見据えろ
gaze into the distance.
最後にわしゃったの壁 指先は鉄の匂い
At last, I've paid my debts. The tips of my fingers smell like iron.
進めはじけどの道混むでしょう
Press forward, pluck those strings!
背後にはシャッターの壁
Behind me is a wall of shutters
指先は鉄の匂い
My fingertips reek of iron
進めはじけどの道混むでしょ
Keep going and burst out; every road is packed
Find a way ここから
Find a way out of here
Found out 見つける
We'll find it out
Rockを奏でろ
Rock out!
遠くを見据えろ
Look far ahead!
息継ぎさえできない街の中
You can't ever take a breather in the city
星空が最高の舞台
The starry sky is the best stage
カラスたちがカーカーと鳴くよ
The crows loudly caw
いつも思うよ いつ寝てるんだろ
I always wonder when am I sleeping
Find a way あたしも
I'll find a way too
Song for 歌うよ
I'll sing a song for you
Rockを響かせ Crowと歌うよ
Shout out that rock! I'll sing with the crows
いつまでこんなところにいる
How long will you be in this sort of place?
そういうやつもいた気がする
I felt you were that kind of guy
うるさいことだけ言うのなら
If whining is all you do
漆黒の羽にさらわれてきこえてくる
Then let the jet black wings take you away into nothing
全力でももう倒れそうだ
I already feel like I'm about to fall with all my power
指もすり切れていた痛い
My fingers are scratched up and they hurt
でもねやるよ
But you know what? I'll keep playing
今夜もビッグなストーリー
Tonight will also be a big story
Find a way ここから
Find a way out of here
Found out 見つける
We'll find it out
Rockを奏でろ
Rock out!
Luckを歌うよ
I'll sing for luck
いつまでだってここにいるよ
I'll continue to be here
通り過ぎていく人の中に
Where the people pass by
闇にとざされたステージで
On the stage closed off by the darkness
今希望の歌歌うよ
Now I'll sing a song of hope
あなただって疲れてるでしょ その背中にも届けたいよ
You must be tired too, I want this song to reach you
こんな暗闇の中からの 希望照らす光の歌を
From within such a darkness, the song of light shines with hope
その歌を
This very song
もうすぐ時計は6時
It's almost 6 o'clock
もうそこに一番星
And now I see the first star
影を踏んで 夜に紛れたくなる帰り道
On my way back home, I surrender to the night
どんなに探してみても 一つしかない星
No matter what way I look, there's only one star
何億光年 離れたところからあんなに輝く
Shining oh so bright, millions of light-years away
いいな 君はみんなから愛されて
You must be so lucky, loved by everyone
「いいや 僕は ずっと一人きりさ」
"You can't see how lonely, the stars are"
君と集まって星座になれたら
If I could be a constellation with you
星降る夜 一瞬の願い事
On every starry night, bringing every wish to light
きらめいて ゆらめいて 震えているシグナル
Shimmering and gently trembling signals
君と集まって星座になれたら
If I could be a constellation with you
空見上げて 指を差せるような
Looking up at the sky where we can point
つないだ線 解かないで
Don't let our connected line break
僕がどんなに眩しくても
No matter how dazzling I become
もうすぐ時計は8時
It's almost 8 o'clock
夜空に満天の星
Bright stars filling the night sky
どんなにまぶしくても
No matter how dazzling you are...
もうすぐ時計は6時
Soon the clock will strike 6
もうそこに一番星
The first star is already there
影を踏んで 夜に紛れたくなる帰り道
Stepping on my shadow on my way home
どんなに探してみても 一つしかない星
No matter how much I search, there's only one star
何億光年 離れたところからはもう
Shining from hundreds of millions of light-years away
ないかももう 知れない
Nai, maybe it's not even there anymore...
月が綺麗で 泣きそうになるのは
The moon is so beautiful it makes me want to cry
いつの日か 別れが来るから
Because someday a parting will come
君と集まって星座になれたら
If you and I could come together and be a constellation
水星みたい 流れるひとりごと
Like a comet, a passing soliloquy
消えていく残像は 真夜中のプリズム
The fading afterimage is a midnight prism
君と集まって星座になれたら
If you and I could come together and be a constellation
切なる願い 誰かに届いたら
If my earnest wish reaches someone
変わるのかな 夜のふちを
Will it change? Even someone like me
なぞるような こんな僕でも
Trace the edge of the night
はるかかなた 僕らは出会ってしまった
Far away, we happened to meet
カルマだから 何度も出会ってしまうよ
Because it's karma, we'll meet over and over again
雲のすきまで
Between the gaps in the clouds
君と集まって星座になれたら
If you and I could come together and be a constellation
夜ひろげて 描こう絵空事
Opening up the night, let's draw an idle fantasy
暗闇を照らすような 満月じゃなくても
Even if it's not a full moon illuminating the darkness
だから集まって星座になりたい
That's why I want to come together and be a constellation
いろどりどりの光 放ような
Like releasing a myriad of colorful lights
つないだ線 ほどけないよ
I won't untie the connected line
君がどんなにまぶしくても
No matter how dazzling you are
午前二時 フミキリに 望遠鏡を担いでいた
At 2:00 AM, I carried a telescope to the railroad crossing
ベルトに結んだラジオ 雨は降らないらしい
The radio tied to my belt said it wouldn't rain
二分後に君が来た 大袈裟な荷物背負って来た
Two minutes later, you came, carrying exaggerated luggage
始めようか 天体観測 ほうき星を探して
Shall we begin astronomical observation, searching for a shooting star?
深い闇に呑まれないように 精一杯だった
I tried my hardest not to be swallowed by the deep darkness
君の震える手を 握ろうとした あの日は
On that day when I tried to hold your trembling hand
見えないモノを見ようとて 望遠鏡を覗き込んだ
I looked into the telescope, trying to see the invisible
静寂を切り裂いて いくつも声が生まれたよ
Tearing through the silence, many voices were born
明日が僕らを呼んだって 返事もろくにしなかった
Even when tomorrow called out to us, I barely replied
「イマ」という ほうき星 君と二人追いかけていた
Chasing together with you, a shooting star called "Now"
静寂を切り裂いていくつもの声が生まれたよ
Several voices were born, cutting through the silence.
明日が僕らを呼んだって 返事もろくにしなかった
Even when tomorrow called out to us, we barely bothered to reply.
「イマ」というほうき星 君と二人追いかけていた
We were chasing a comet called "Now", the two of us together.
気が付けばいつでも ひたむき何か探している
Before we knew it, we were always earnestly searching for something.
幸せの定義とか 悲しみの置き場とか
The definition of happiness, where to put our sorrows...
生まれたら死ぬまで ずっと探しているさあ
We keep searching for them from birth until death, so...
始めようか天体観測 ほうき星を探して
Let's begin our astronomical observation, searching for the comet.
今までに見つけたものは 全部覚えている
I remember everything I've found up until now.
君の震える手を 握れなかった痛みも
Even the pain of not being able to hold your trembling hand,
知らないものを知ろうとして 望遠鏡を覗き込んだ
I peered through the telescope, trying to know what I didn't know.
暗闇を照らすような 微かな光探したよ
Searching for a faint light that would illuminate the darkness.
そして知った痛みを 未だに僕は覚えている
And the pain I came to know then, I still remember to this day.
「イマ」というほうき星 今も一人追いかけている
I'm still chasing that comet called "Now" all by myself.
背が伸びるにつれて 伝えたいことも増えていた
As I grew taller, the things I wanted to tell you also increased.
宛のない手紙も 崩れる程重くなった僕は元気でいるよ
Letters with no address became heavy enough to collapse. I'm doing well,
心配事も少ないよ
and I don't have many worries.
ただ一つ 今も思い出すよ
Only one thing I still remember:
予報外れの雨に打たれて 泣き出しそうな
Beaten by unforecasted rain, looking as if you're about to cry,
君の震える手を 握れなかったあの時を
that time when I couldn't hold your trembling hand.
見えてるものを見落として 望遠鏡をまた担いで
Overlooking what is visible, I hoisted the telescope once more,
静寂と闇の帰り道を 駆け抜けた
and ran through the way home of silence and darkness.
そして知った痛みが 未だに僕を支えている
And the pain I came to know then still supports me.
「イマ」というほうき星 今も一人追いかけている
I'm still chasing that comet called "Now" all by myself.
もう一度君に会おうとして 望遠鏡をまた担いで
Trying to meet you once more, I hoisted the telescope again,
前と同じ午前二時 フミキリまで駆けてくよ
and ran to the railroad crossing at 2 AM, just like before.
始めようか天体観測 二分後に君が来なくとも
Let's begin our astronomical observation, even if you don't come two minutes later.
「イマ」というほうき星 君と二人追いかけている
We were chasing the comet called "Now", the two of us together.
広い宇宙の数ある一つ
In the vast universe, out of many,
青い地球の広い世界で
in the wide world of the blue Earth,
小さな恋の思いは届く
a small feeling of love reaches out,
小さな島のあなたのものへ
to you on a small island.
響け 恋の歌
Resonate, love song.
あなたにとって 大事な人ほど
The more important someone is to you,
すぐそばにいるの
the closer they are to you.
握りしめた手 話すことなく
Holding hands tightly without letting go,
想いは強く 永遠誓う
feelings are strong, eternally sworn.
それでも二人 涙にかわり
Even so, changing tears
喜びになり 言葉できず
into joy, unable to put into words,
ただ抱きしめる ただ抱きしめる
just embracing, just embracing.
ほら あなたにとって 大事な人ほど
Look, the more important someone is to you,
すぐそばにいるの
the closer they are to you.
ただ あなたにだけ 届いてほしい
I just want it to reach only you,
響け 恋の歌
resonate, love song.
ほら
Look...
響け 恋の歌
Resonate, love song.
夢ならば覚めないで
If it's a dream, don't wake me up,
if it's a dream, don't wake me up.
あなたと過ごした時 永遠の星となる
The time spent with you becomes an eternal star.
ほら あなたにとって 大事な人ほど
Look, the more important someone is to you,
すぐそばにいるの
the closer they are to you.
ただ あなたにだけ 届いてほしい
I just want it to reach only you,
響け 恋の歌
resonate, love song.
ほら あなたにとって 大事な人ほど
Look, the more important someone is to you,
すぐそばにいるの
the closer they are to you.
ただ あなたにだけ 届いてほしい
I just want it to reach only you,
響け 恋の歌
resonate, love song.
ほら
Look...
響け 恋の歌
Resonate, love song.
ここで、一つ…
Here, one thing...
マリンからお知らせがあります。えっ？
Marine has an announcement. Eh?
なんか聞いてる？
Did you hear anything?
今日でこのバンドは…解散します！えっ！？
Starting today, this band is... disbanding! Eh!?
えーっ！？
Eeh!?!
うっそでしょ？
You're kidding, right?
マリンにはやりたいことがあるんだ。やりたいこと？
Marine has something she wants to do. Something she wants to do?
みんな、さようなら。
Everyone, goodbye.
え？待って待って！
Eh? Wait, wait!
ってどういうこと？
What does that mean?
え？
Eh?
うっそでしょ。
You're kidding, right?
はあ、マリンどうしてるかなあ。
Haa, I wonder how Marine is doing.
テレビ見ない？
Want to watch TV?
見よ見よ。
Let's watch, let's watch.
よいしょっと。
Here we go.
特報
[Title: Special Bulletin]
特報ですよ！
It's a special bulletin!
私無罪よ！
I'm innocent!
港となんかじゃしゃげないわ、近頃までは
I won't get carried away at any port, until recently
宝箱の底しまい込んでほしい気分
I want you to keep it tucked away at the bottom of the treasure chest.
ギュッと抱きしめて、リリージャボムはい！
Hug me tight, Lily Jaboom, yes!
君の一番目指して暴走よ、そろそろ
Racing toward your number one spot, any time now.
本当は心配ないけど頑張っちゃう！
Though I'm actually not worried, I'll do my best!
このあと22時プレミア公開！！
[Title: Premiere at 22:00 later tonight!!]
ドキドキしてる！
My heart is racing!
美少女無罪♡パイレーツ マリリン マリリン マリリンの無罪！
Bishoujo Muzai Pirates! Marilyn, Marilyn, Marilyn's innocence!
やっぱギラギラ 真っっ白白！
After all, it's dazzling, pure white!
ねえ、言ってよねえ 年齢なんて関係ないってさ そういうめんどくさいのも含めて愛してく るって！
Hey, tell me, age doesn't matter, and that you'll love me even with all that troublesome stuff!
ねえねえ、言ってよねえ 言ってない？ ふーん、そういうこと言うんだ。
Hey hey, tell me, didn't you say so? Hmph, so that's how it is.
ちなみにこの船では美女生無罪が適用されますけど？
By the way, the "beauty innocence" rule applies on this ship, you know?
任せて！魔法で若返り
Leave it to me! Rejuvenated by magic!
ねぇ、言ったよね？年齢なんて関係ないってさ
Hey, didn't you say? Age doesn't matter,
そういうめんどくさいのも含めて愛してくれるって
and that you'd love me even with all that trouble.
ねぇねぇ、言ったよね？言ってない？
Hey hey, didn't you say? Or did you not?
ふーん、そう言うんだ。
Hm, so that's how it is.
ちなみにこの船では美少女無罪が適用されます、だけど？
By the way, on this ship, "Cute Girl Not Guilty" applies, but...?
まかせて！魔法で若返り
Leave it to me! Rejuvenated by magic,
ヒミツの素顔はキミにだけ
my secret face is just for you.
トクベツ ですよ～？
It's special, okay?
ah… アタシ厄介 よ
Ah... I'm a handful, you know.
ah… 港 なんか じゃ
Ah... as for harbors and such,
はしゃげない わ 近頃 はね
I can't get too excited lately,
宝 の 島 に し て ほしい 気分
so I feel like making it my treasure island!
出航ー！！
Set sail!!
キュートは正義 美少女無罪
Cute is justice, cute girl not guilty,
キミの一番目指して ヨーソロ！
aiming to be your number one, yosoro!
本当は自信ない けど頑張っちゃう
Actually I'm not confident, but I'll try my best!
きゅっ きゅっ きゅるん きゅっ きゅっ きゅるんるん
Kyu kyu kyurun, kyu kyu kyurunrun,
恋する 気持ち17歳
feeling of love, 17 years old.
0時になっちゃうわ オトナの時間
It turns midnight, adult time.
ド・キ・ド・キ・して rouge ？
Thumping heart with rouge?
まだ 早い ♡
Still too early ♡
だっただめですか フリル の 服 着たら
Is it really no good if I wear frilly clothes?
(そんなこと、ないよ)
(No way, that's not true)
だっただって魔法少女になってみたい
Because, because, I want to become a magical girl!
ギリアリ 有罪 ！？
Barely guilty!?
針路 は なん なん 星
Our course is whatever-star,
ちょっぴり 足 ん ない 積極性 ？
with a little lacking proactiveness?
結局 キミ も もっと 若い 子 ？
After all, do you prefer younger girls?
なんだって する から 見捨て ない で 、キミ たち ！
I'll do anything, so don't abandon me, you guys!
ちょっと イイ トコ 見せ て みたー い ！
I want to show off a cool side!
ah… たまに いじけ ちゃう
Ah... sometimes I get sulky,
ah… それでも いい の ？
ah... but is that still okay?
年頃 だ もん 本気 に し ちゃう
I'm at that age, so I'll take it seriously!
嵐 の 中 も
Even in the middle of a storm
一緒 に 、行こう ！！
let's go together!!
ハートに チャーム 美少女無罪
Charm on my heart, cute girl not guilty,
あれあれ どう した の ？
what, what happened?
めんどくさい よ なんて 言え ちゃっ て
Saying "what a pain" while
かまっ て くれる キミ が 好き
paying attention to me—I love you!
きゅっ きゅっ きゅるん きゅっ きゅっ きゅるんるん
Kyu kyu kyurun, kyu kyu kyurunrun,
優しく し て ね 17歳
be nice to me, 17 years old.
突っ込ん で 経験値 お楽しみ chu ♡
Dive in and enjoy the experience points chu ♡
ド・キ・ド・キ・して rouge ？
Thumping heart with rouge?
まだ 早い ♡
Still too early ♡
だっただめですか フリル の 服 着たら
Is it really no good if I wear frilly clothes?
だっただって魔法少女になってみたい
Because, because, I want to become a magical girl!
離さ ない で つかまっ て い て
Don't let go, hold on tight,
世界 の 広 さ 見せ て あげる から ！！
I'll show you how vast the world is!!
キュートは正義 美少女無罪
Cute is justice, cute girl not guilty,
キミの一番目指して ヨーソロ！
aiming to be your number one, yosoro!
冗談 も 大好き だ けど 真剣 よ
Jokes are great too, but I mean it seriously.
きゅっ きゅっ きゅるん きゅっ きゅっ きゅるんるん
Kyu kyu kyurun, kyu kyu kyurunrun,
恋する 気持ち17歳
feeling of love, 17 years old.
0時になっちゃうわ オトナの時間
It turns midnight, adult time.
ド・キ・ド・キ・して rouge ？
Thumping heart with rouge?
まだ 早い ♡
Still too early ♡
無罪 ！ 無罪 ！ 美少女無罪 ！
Innocent! Innocent! Cute girl not guilty!
マリン ！ マリン ！ マリン は 無罪 ！
Marine! Marine! Marine is innocent!
“マリン” じゃなくて
Instead of "Marine",
“マリン 船長” だろうん !?
it's "Captain Marine", right!?
はい！ということで、早速ですが今お披露目した船長の新オリジナル曲
Yes! So, right away, Captain's new original song
「美少女無罪♡パイレーツ」はこのあと22時からプレミア公開となっています！
"Bishoujo Muzai♡Pirates" will have its premiere release tonight at 22:00!
「Unison」「マリ箱」に引き続いてのアニメチームにさらに増員して
Following "Unison" and "MariBako", the anime team was further expanded,
今までで一番すごい映像になったと思います！！
and I think it became the most amazing video ever!!
そしてなんと！今回は船長も人生初のアニメ原画に参加させていただきました！
And what's more! This time, Captain participated in animation key frames for the very first time!
船長が担当した箇所がどこか是非探してみてください！今度答え合わせしましょう！
Please try to find which part Captain was in charge of! We'll check the answers next time!
楽曲はナナホシ管弦楽団様に書いていただきました！マリンの一味へ向けたラブソングとなっております
The song was written by Nanahoshi Orchestra-sama! It's a love song addressed to Marine's crew,
ぜひ船長の愛を受け取るためにたくさん聞いてください！！
so please listen to it a lot to receive Captain's love!!
このあと24時からは各種音楽サイトで配信もありますよ～！
Starting at 24:00 tonight, it will also be available on various music streaming sites~!
さらにさらになんですが！Amazon Musicさんのプレイリスト「VIRtuality」でこの曲をプッシュしてもらえることになりました！！
And what's more! This song has been chosen for a push on Amazon Music's playlist "VIRtuality"!!
キミたちいっぱい聞いてください！
You guys, listen to it a lot!
そしてなんと、全国のカラオケDAMで明日31日から歌えます！早い！
And what's more, you can sing it starting tomorrow, the 31st, at nationwide karaoke DAM! So fast!
本人映像(MV)も8月1日から順次配信開始になります！
The official MV will also be distributed starting August 1st!
ぜひカラオケで仲間にも布教してみてください！
Please try spreading it to your friends at karaoke!
さらに、船長がDAMチャンネルにも出演予定ですのでお楽しみに！
Furthermore, Captain is also scheduled to appear on DAM Channel, so look forward to it!
まだあります！あの、新宿駅東口のクロス新宿ビジョンにて、
There's still more! At Cross Shinjuku Vision in front of Shinjuku Station East Exit,
「美少女無罪♡パイレーツ」の90秒のMV放映が決定しましたーー！！！
a 90-second MV screening of "Bishoujo Muzai♡Pirates" has been decided--!!!
新宿駅東口のあの有名な猫ちゃんのところですね！
That's right at that famous cat place in front of Shinjuku Station East Exit!
期間は8月1日から8月15日7時から25時までですね！
The period is from August 1st to August 15th, from 7:00 to 25:00!
体調管理にお気を付けくださいね！もうこんな感じで、お楽しみが目白押しです！
Please take care of your health when you go to see it! Enjoy!
もうこんな感じで、お楽しみが盛りだくさんです！
There are so many fun things in store for you!
ワクワクしながらいっぱい聞いて待っていてくださいね！
Please look forward to it and listen closely!
続いての告知です！
Now for the next announcement!
実はあの日常侵食ホラーゲーム「つぐのひ」とマリンがコラボさせて頂けることが決定しました～！
Actually, it's been decided that Marine will collaborate with the everyday horror game "Tsugunohi"!
そして本日は、なんと！今日の配信を見ているキミたちに開発中のゲーム画面を特別にチラ見せしちゃいます！
And today, surprise! We're giving you guys watching the stream a special sneak peek of the game in development!
操作は左に進むだけ
[Visual Text: Controls: Just walk to the left]
その“美貌”に隠された秘密―
[Visual Text: The secret hidden behind that "beauty"—]
海賊船の甲板にいるのは主人公…って、
Is that the protagonist on the pirate ship deck...?
もしかして樽に入っているのは船長がOL時代にボーナスの代わりに受け取った段ボールみかん！？
Wait, could that cardboard box of mandarins in the barrel be what the Captain received as a bonus back when she was an office worker!?
そんな「美魔女の真実」は2023年8月11日金曜日に発売予定！詳しくはつぐのひ公式アカウントさんをチェックですよ～！
"The Truth of the Beautiful Witch" is scheduled for release on Friday, August 11, 2023! Check the official Tsugunohi account for details!
続いてはお楽しみのグッズのお知らせです！
Next up is an announcement for our exciting merchandise!
めっちゃほしいものしかないですよ！まずはこちら！
There are only things you'll definitely want! First is this!
あかさあい先生描きおろしのラバーマットです！机に敷いたりカードゲームしたり飾ったり…まあ好きにしてください！海賊の宝の地図風デザインなので机に置いてあるだけで船長気分を味わえますよ！キミも陸海賊にならないか！？
It's a rubber mat illustrated by Akasa Ai-sensei! Put it on your desk, use it for card games, display it... whatever you like! It's designed like a pirate treasure map, so just having it on your desk will make you feel like a captain! Won't you become a land pirate too!?
続いてランダムラバーストラップです！こちらはね船長が描き下ろしました！前回はなかった衣装や髪型ものなのでこれは欲しいですよね！がんばって描いたのでぜひゲットしてください！
Next is the random rubber strap! This was drawn by the Captain! It features outfits and hairstyles we didn't have last time, so you definitely want this! I worked hard on drawing it, so please be sure to get it!
そしてこれは欲しいでしょ！おでかけマリンぬいぐるみです！顔面はね船長が描かせていただいて監修しました！かわいい顔で届きますように～！ちっちゃいぬいぐるみなのでぜひ持ち運んだり胸の谷間に挟んだり小物入れに入れたりしてください！あ、小物入れ持ってないですか？ならこれはどうですか！？
And you definitely want this! The Outing Marine plushie! The face was drawn and supervised by the Captain! I hope it arrives with a cute face~! Since it's a tiny plushie, please carry it around, tuck it in your cleavage, or put it in an accessory pouch! Oh, you don't have an accessory pouch? Well, how about this!?
マリ箱です！はいこちらマリ箱のミュージックビデオに出てくる船長が閉じ込められている箱を再現していただきました！この中に対さっきのマリぬいをぶっ込んで遊んだり大切なものをぶっ込んだり飾ったまま一生開けなかったり自由に使ってくださいね！
The Mari Box! Yes, this faithfully recreates the box where the Captain is trapped in the "Mari Box" music video! Feel free to play by stuffing the Marine plushie inside, toss in your precious items, or leave it on display without ever opening it for the rest of your life!
こちらすべて購入のフルセット特典は直筆メッセージ入りポストカードと船長が耳を舐めようとしてギリ舐めないASMRボイスがついてきま～す！直筆メッセージは数量限定なのでなくなり次第複製メッセージになりますがこちらも愛を込めて書きますね！ASMRボイスは絶対ついてくるのでアドしか無い！
The full set bonus for purchasing all of these includes a handwritten message postcard and an ASMR voice where the Captain tries to lick your ear but narrowly misses~! The handwritten messages are in limited quantities, so once they run out they'll be duplicated messages, but I'll write them with love too! The ASMR voice definitely comes with it, so it's all upside!
というわけでこのあとは「美少女無罪♡パイレーツ」ものすごいミュージックビデオに見に行ってくださいね！船長が原画描いたところを探してくださいね～！それではいきますよ～！出航～！！
With that said, go check out the incredible music video for "Bishoujyo Muzai Pirates" right after this! See if you can find the parts where the Captain drew the original art~! Here we go~! Set sail!!
ド・キ・ド・キ・して rouge ？
Making your heart go dokidoki with rouge?
いきますよ～！
Here we go~!
（無罪！無罪！美少女無罪！）
(Innocent! Innocent! Beautiful girl innocent!)
（マリン！マリン！マリンは無罪！）
(Marine! Marine! Marine is innocent!)
（やっぱりキラキラもっとクラクラ）
(Always sparkling, even more dizzying)
ねぇ、言ったよね？
Hey, you told me, right?
年齢なんて関係ないってさ
That age doesn't matter at all,
そういうめんどくさいのも
And that even those troublesome things
含めて愛してくれるって
Are included in your love for me.